[{"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3b", "question": "Which element appears seventh on the periodic table?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339090", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was the god of the underworld?", "answer": "Hades", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf95", "question": "Sweetbread is derived from what organ?", "answer": "Pancreas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a8d", "question": "In the series \"Eragon\", what is the name of Eragon's dragon?", "answer": "Saphira", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b711", "question": "What contribution to Christmas is John Calcott Horsely credited with?", "answer": "The first mass-produced Christmas card", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b7", "question": "What are brails and buntlines on a ship?", "answer": "Ropes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa49c6ce05a3942286eb5", "question": "The Stay Puff Marshmallow Man originally appeared in which film?", "answer": "Ghostbusters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3b7", "question": "Which ocean is the world's largest ocean?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600394d257a0e35c43f8388e", "question": "What painting technique was employed by Ribera, and other painters, in order to focus a spotlight on certain areas of a painting?", "answer": "Tenebrism", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e5", "question": "Guitarist Brian May was part of what popular band?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb53", "question": "How deep is each end zone on a CFL football field?", "answer": "20 yards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf5", "question": "In what movies is the Okinawan sword-maker Hattori Hanzo a character?", "answer": "Kill Bill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b138", "question": "What Greek physician is known as \"The Father of Medicine\"?", "answer": "Hippocrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933b", "question": "On the TV show \"South Park\", which character wears a blue hat with a red pom-pom on it?", "answer": "Stan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2c", "question": "Who is Gwyneth Paltrow's mother?", "answer": "Blythe Danner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e9b", "question": "What movie did the villain Harry Powell appear in?", "answer": "The Night of the Hunter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d9922596a59cbdfbd3c7", "question": "Which Joseph Glidden invention put an end to open-range cattle drives?", "answer": "Barbed wire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe733d9eec85e375820b226", "question": "What was the code name for the Battle of Okinawa?", "answer": "Operation Iceberg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388dc", "question": "As punishment for not appreciating Apollo's music, King Midas's ears were transformed into the ears of what animal?", "answer": "Donkey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec89acec223966ae8f8829", "question": "\"Fear takes flight\" is the tagline for what 2005 film?", "answer": "\"Red Eye\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b916", "question": "What 2 letters in scrabble have the highest point value?", "answer": "Q and Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec26898dc25ca9e12ef64c", "question": "How many engines are on a B-52 bomber?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c9", "question": "What was Audrey Hepburn's real last name?", "answer": "Ruston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73b", "question": "What psychiatrist developed the principal of \"synchronicity\"?", "answer": "Carl Jung", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf1", "question": "What was the French film \"The Emperor's March\" renamed for US audiences?", "answer": "March of the Penguins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3dd", "question": "Which is Europe's second largest island after Great Britain?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600240d84be4723ccac2216a", "question": "In the novel \"Dances with Wolves,\" what Native-American nation did John J. Dunbar engage?", "answer": "Lakota", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b32316fbf195a31e15d7384", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3d", "question": "What disease devastated America's population of Elm trees?", "answer": "Dutch Elm Disease", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015ebcafe83fe1f2a824bfa", "question": "What fall festival activity did the Romans bring to Britain when they invaded?", "answer": "Bobbing for apples", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28b", "question": "Which ear can most people hear better with?", "answer": "The right", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff14621b0ee8c595b6d39bf", "question": "Which classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ced", "question": "What is the Heart of Gold in \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "A spaceship", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ec9d08d98002fdd633bd", "question": "Equatorial Guinea gained independence from which country in 1968?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d0", "question": "What is a turkey stuffed with a duck stuffed with a chicken called?", "answer": "Turducken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600242814be4723ccac22187", "question": "In the novel by Cervantes, what is the name of the simple farmer who Don Quixote recruits to be his squire?", "answer": "Sancho Panza", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef64f86ce05a3942286e68", "question": "What breed of dog portrayed Toto in 1939's \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Cairn terrier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7a41ff048f679a45abe9", "question": "Which constellation are the stars Castor and Pollux in?", "answer": "Gemini", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a041", "question": "Kevin Spacey plays Francis Underwood in what Netflix original series?", "answer": "House of Cards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a1e1e25b5a031299b74573f", "question": "Which present-day country in the Southern hemisphere did the Dutch reach in 1606?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d79", "question": "What tunnel does Tony Soprano use in the \"Sopranos\" opening credits?", "answer": "The Lincoln Tunnel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f22", "question": "In a symphony orchestra, what instrument is played by the concertmaster?", "answer": "Violin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c36ad815febcc896f9269", "question": "Who runs the \"Leftorium\"?", "answer": "Ned Flanders", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bee", "question": "What year did singer Cherilyn Sarkisian La Piere Bono Allman legally change her name to just Cher?", "answer": "1978", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ff", "question": "What was the name of the first human in space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f4a", "question": "What Latin phrase actually comes from a poem, attributed to Virgil, about a salad recipe?", "answer": "E Pluribus Unum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c772", "question": "Which planet is named for the Roman God who was the son of Juno and Jupiter?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d33", "question": "What 1813 novel was turned into a movie starring Keira Knightly in 2005?", "answer": "Pride and Prejudice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924e", "question": "Who plays Will Turner in the movie \"Pirates of the Caribbean\"?", "answer": "Orlando Bloom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1cb", "question": "Which group had a hit with the song \"Back for Good\" in 1995?", "answer": "Take That", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf52", "question": "What is the name of the Danish parliament?", "answer": "The Folketing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f564b533a95c66dc4fe751", "question": "Who played the character of Evelyn Mulwray in the 1974 film \"Chinatown\"?", "answer": "Faye Dunaway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa3420565ad31a57c812", "question": "Who was President Gerald Ford's vice president?", "answer": "Nelson Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdd5d0a0499cffc60b84230", "question": "Who led the Solidarity movement and became President of Poland in 1990?", "answer": "Lech Walesa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba18c874c93a3298b2127", "question": "Of which US state was Jimmy Carter Governor before he became president?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988a", "question": "What instrument is Questlove most famous for playing?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede4a26ce05a3942286ddf", "question": "In 1994, Elton John wrote the songs for which Disney animated film with lyricist Tim Rice?", "answer": "\"The Lion King\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77d", "question": "What precious stones were originally used to polish axes in the Stone Age?", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5eb73cea5e259d7869087332", "question": "A \"waltz-length\" dress stops at what part of the body?", "answer": "The calf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec238b8dc25ca9e12ef631", "question": "What nationality was Fr\u00e9d\u00e9ric Chopin?", "answer": "Polish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d9", "question": "Who was Martina Navratilova's usual ladies doubles partner in the 1980's?\u00a0", "answer": "Pam Shriver\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f8", "question": "What lizard can be 10 feet long?", "answer": "The Komodo dragon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e94d1fc5ea27d7a1303aed6", "question": "In what US state is the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9384a6bd93ce3a4e5f682", "question": "Insectophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b080e662d71a53650fc9", "question": "Paris\u2019s Centre Pompidou has what architectural quirk?", "answer": "It is \"inside-out\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b07", "question": "What is the name of the Wally World mascot in \"National Lampoon's Vacation\"?", "answer": "Marty Moose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede2126ce05a3942286dcc", "question": "In 1996, Nintendo celebrated a milestone in the number of game cartridges sold with how many?", "answer": "One billion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c829", "question": "What is the liquid component of blood called?", "answer": "Plasma", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ebf", "question": "Whose girlfriends are named Callie Shaw and Iola Morton?", "answer": "The Hardy Boys", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37a", "question": "What is the five-letter name for a young dog?", "answer": "Whelp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede1366ce05a3942286dc3", "question": "In the 2006 movie \"Flicka,\" what type of animal is Flicka?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc1196de0eb824d4052dd", "question": "What is Australia's top export?", "answer": "Coal briquettes -- Australia is the world's largest exporter of coal briquettes.  It exports most of its goods to China and Japan.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d06d3a870e6f05ba600857", "question": "Secretary birds are native to which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a58f", "question": "What U.S. state has the longest freshwater shoreline?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc5", "question": "Who is the wife in Shakespeare's only interracial married couple?", "answer": "Desdemona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff14127b0ee8c595b6d39a1", "question": "Jackson Pollock was known for what distinctive painting method?", "answer": "Drip technique", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b7", "question": "What is the more common name for grape sugar?", "answer": "Glucose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa8bc6ce05a3942286ed6", "question": "Who played the part of Max Cady in the 1962 thriller \"Cape Fear\"?", "answer": "Robert Mitchum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecb", "question": "What French word for \"jewel\" became a common name for American movie houses?", "answer": "Bijou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0aa", "question": "What kind of a head does a Criosphinx possess?", "answer": "Ram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a310", "question": "Which 1979 film featured a space ship named \"Nostromo\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2146c31a458464a93c456", "question": "When was the last time Easter Sunday and April Fool's Day occurred on the same day in the 20th century?", "answer": "1956", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab977986faa38a764be529", "question": "On what vehicle was the Mutt Cutts Van based on in the 1994 film \"Dumb and Dumber\"?", "answer": "1984 Ford Econoline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e9", "question": "Which actor received the first Academy Award?", "answer": "Emil Jannings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ace6", "question": "Which country was former Prime Minister Tony Blair born in?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a971", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The House of Lords?", "answer": "The United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d9", "question": "What city boasted the world's first subway line?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb33", "question": "In 1964, who became the first running back in NFL history to rush for more than 10,000 career yards?", "answer": "Jim Brown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33d", "question": "Why, in 1969, did the French flag appear on some British postage stamps?", "answer": "To commemorate concorde's maiden flight", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bfa", "question": "Mark Rothko is best known for his work in what genre of painting?", "answer": "Abstract", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a659", "question": "Which eastern US state is home to the Kittatinny Mountains?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf6", "question": "What drink is sometimes called \"the green fairy\"?", "answer": "Absinthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a69d", "question": "The Shenandoah Valley is located in which eastern US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a1a48612f2a7826b9b8731", "question": "In Greek mythology, Dione was the mother of which goddess?", "answer": "Aphrodite", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d9", "question": "Which is heavier, a baseball or a softball?", "answer": "A softball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f168fcf7c52aae91cc07cc", "question": "In what film did Elvis play a double role?", "answer": "Kissin' Cousins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25d1bb63e5727cf5a4862", "question": "Michael Jackson's video for \"Black or White\" featured which famous child actor?", "answer": "Macaulay Culkin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa0", "question": "What is the capital of Niger?", "answer": "Niamey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e95a47ccba3ffe45786e2", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Rigoletto\"?", "answer": "Giuseppe Verdi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe773cceec85e375820b30d", "question": "The Cherokee rose is the state flower of which U.S. state?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6aa9220565ad31a57c81b", "question": "What was Hoover Dam's original name?", "answer": "Boulder Dam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a998d61d1b4d384d5d69c", "question": "What year did the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" end its 20 season run?", "answer": "1975", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e7", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a seashell?", "answer": "Conchiglie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d5", "question": "What British rock-and-roll legend recorded a 1975 album titled \"Venus and Mars\"?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339227", "question": "What decade did Marty McFly go back to in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "1950's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feba9907e83c707845b20d6", "question": "What breed of dog's evidence is first legally admissible in court?", "answer": "The Bloodhound is the first breed of dog that's evidence is legally admissible in some U.S. courts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f08", "question": "What band would walk 500 miles and 500 more just to fall down at your door?", "answer": "The Proclaimers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae85f5b4007905755f79e8b", "question": "What is the highest mountain in Africa?", "answer": "Mount Kilimanjaro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3a", "question": "Thomas Jefferson is depicted on what US coin?", "answer": "5 cent coin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ee", "question": "Beantown is the nickname for what US city?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a213", "question": "What cartoon, from the Talkertoon series, marked the first appearance of Betty Boop?", "answer": "Dizzy Dishes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb71", "question": "In 1992, what city hosted the first World Series game ever played outside the US?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c13d", "question": "What instrument is jazz musician Charlie Mingus mostly associated with?", "answer": "Double Bass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca7", "question": "The adjective \"callipygian\" refers to someone who has a beautiful what?", "answer": "Butt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f58", "question": "Which villain did Michael Shannon play in the 2013 movie \"The Man of Steel\"?", "answer": "General Zod", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a052", "question": "What 2015 big screen adaptation of an 1980s cartoon was pulled from cinemas after just two weeks due to poor ticket sales?", "answer": "Jem and the Holograms", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339662", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Krusty's monkey?", "answer": "Mr. Teeny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c424", "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59068253ff9c0647b50a809c", "question": "How much money did buyers interested in Tesla\u2019s Model 3 vehicle, had to pay as a deposit?", "answer": "US$1,000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a65a", "question": "What is the capital of Montana?", "answer": "Helena", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe36b370ada16518afdc03a", "question": "What is next in this sequence: era, period, ...?", "answer": "Epoch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad80", "question": "In 1943, the \"One Thousand Mile War\" began when Japan invaded what set of islands?", "answer": "Aleutian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fcc1a23c97eb73f6a51a26c", "question": "What was Tom Hardy's first feature film?", "answer": "Black Hawk Down", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c02e", "question": "Who is Reginald Kenneth Dwight otherwise known as?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d0", "question": "Who opened the first \"cinema\" in Paris in 1895?", "answer": "The Lumiere Brothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c214", "question": "Which country were the 1932 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc55", "question": "Who was the first woman to head the International Montary Fund?", "answer": "Christine Lagarde", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b474", "question": "What year did Andre and Edouard Michelin first publish the \"Michelin Guide\"?", "answer": "1900", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fd", "question": "What was the better known name of the old 91 meters sprint race?", "answer": "100 yards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b530e662d71a53650ff6", "question": "Writing for a newspaper, what did Edgar Allan Poe encourage his readers to do?", "answer": "Send him encoded messages.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c91", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Cabot Cove, Maine?", "answer": "Murder, She Wrote", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ea37b24f84e0b9f9ffd1", "question": "An Octagon with equal sides is called a what?", "answer": "A Regular Octagon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d01", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"1984\"?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a37", "question": "Which French term literally means \"Fat Tuesday\"?", "answer": "Mardi Gras", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cdb8ee347d002c297e4de", "question": "\"High Class Baby\" and \"Travellin' Light\" were hits for which singer?", "answer": "Cliff Richard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42c", "question": "The Himalayas are located on which continent?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b627", "question": "What bird has the scientific name struthio camelus?", "answer": "Ostrich", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2b", "question": "What Internet portal was sued for copyright infringement in 2000 by the star of \"Young Einstein\"?", "answer": "Yahoo!", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef9", "question": "What US president was nicknamed \"Honest Abe\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338873", "question": "What mid-day nap takes its name from the Spanish word sexta, meaning sixth?", "answer": "The siesta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac0", "question": "What is the most abundant metal in Earth's core?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae9566574a5ce6b56b8254", "question": "What animals does a hippophobe fear?", "answer": "Horses", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bfe0233b668d7dfe168b5cb", "question": "In Greek mythology, Atlas was a member of what group?", "answer": "The Titans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7eab7b24f84e0b9f9ffd7", "question": "In the port of which city was the Greenpeace flagship Rainbow Warrior sunk in 1985?", "answer": "Auckland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe90a2201dd7bf43be5e896", "question": "The psychological test of human emotions and personality, using inkblots, is formally known as what?", "answer": "The Rorschach test", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f1", "question": "What US state has been governed by Philip La Follette and Tommy Thompson?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf19", "question": "An onomastician studies what?", "answer": "Names", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab74", "question": "Dhaka is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede1eb6ce05a3942286dc8", "question": "In \"Frosty the Snowman\", what are Frosty's eyes made of?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5bb", "question": "What type of milk is traditional feta cheese made of?", "answer": "Sheep's milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b37e", "question": "The Mason-Dixon line ran between Maryland and which other American State?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b1", "question": "What sitcom star did Mt. Airy, North Carolina rename a stretch of Highway 52 after, in 2002?", "answer": "Andy Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc1758469bb8041d07a08f", "question": "What Spanish automobile manufacturer's first model was a three-wheeled two-door car?", "answer": "Kapi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1db", "question": "Greeks consider Tuesday the unluckiest day of the week because what city fell on a Tuesday in 1453?", "answer": "Constantinople", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e86", "question": "What species are mingled to produce a Centaur?", "answer": "Human and horse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60121ac663c99d48cd169b08", "question": "What is the main ingredient of Bombay Duck?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febba037e83c707845b2142", "question": "What is the object that opposing players must destroy in order to win at \"League of Legends\"?", "answer": "Nexus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ac", "question": "How many watts make a kilowatt?", "answer": "1000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908d", "question": "Which Roman God was the equivalent of the Greek God Dionysus?", "answer": "Bacchus, Liber", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d7", "question": "What does MST3K stand for?", "answer": "Mystery Science Theater 3000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c96", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Norwich, Vermont?", "answer": "Newhart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b174634bb2d29f81593b706", "question": "What duo lost their Grammy for Best New Artist in the early 1990's?", "answer": "Milli Vanilli", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d1", "question": "When not fighting crime, what did Underdog do for a living?", "answer": "Shoeshine boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac4", "question": "\"Understood Betsy\" was a book published in 1918 by what author?", "answer": "Dorothy Canfield Fisher", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b13ce662d71a53650fcf", "question": "What is the name of the train station that services Hogwarts School?", "answer": "Hogsmeade Station", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a849", "question": "The historic district of Haight-Ashbury is located in what US city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa54ccc73aa70ea0b70b1f", "question": "In what country are April Fool's jokes climaxed with the saying \"Doroughe sizdah\"?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa8", "question": "Where do fallen Norse warriors go?", "answer": "Valhalla", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f43", "question": "What future \"Cheers\" star plays Mob boss Tommy Como in \"Raging Bull\"?", "answer": "Nicholas \"Coach\" Colasanto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea4910ff048f679a45abb6", "question": "What does \"holistic\" mean in reference to holistic medicine?", "answer": "Addressing the whole person", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015de62fe83fe1f2a824b69", "question": "What Spartan king led a small army of 300 Spartans against a vastly superior Persian force in the Battle of Thermopylae?", "answer": "Leonidas, King of Sparta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8aa1c01dd7bf43be5e757", "question": "What is the Hebrew term for \"commandment\"?", "answer": "Mitzvah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a1", "question": "What is a young female horse called?", "answer": "A filly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab1997baab681b09292192", "question": "What year was NASCAR founded?", "answer": "1948", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aee", "question": "In Greek mythology, what is the name of the god of Dreams?", "answer": "Morpheus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d077e0870e6f05ba600868", "question": "Who directed the 1995 film \"Boys on the Side\"?", "answer": "Herbert Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b3cfe662d71a53650fe3", "question": "What is the official name of Beethoven\u2019s \"Moonlight Sonata\"?", "answer": "Piano Sonata No. 14", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf49", "question": "What is the next-to-last event?", "answer": "Penultimate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbe", "question": "What name was given to the leather protection cowboys wore over the front of their pants?", "answer": "Chaps", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b38b", "question": "Who became UK's Prime Minister following the assassination of Spencer Perceval in 1812?", "answer": "Robert Banks Jenkinson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Marge's bowling ball?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40f", "question": "What year did Bangladesh declare its independence from Pakistan?", "answer": "1971", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb4", "question": "What relation was psychiatrist Anna Freud to Sigmund?", "answer": "Daughter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339101", "question": "Which famous composer wrote the opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "Georges Bizet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a806", "question": "What is the capital of Hungary?", "answer": "Budapest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a0a06c0f9723ab15cb36", "question": "What was the inspiration behind a 12-person jury?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles of Jesus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c715", "question": "What vegetable gets its name from the Latin word for \"branch\"?", "answer": "Broccoli", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5906830bff9c0647b50a80a3", "question": "Which actress, portraying an Alderaan princess, passed away in December, 2016?", "answer": "Carrie Fisher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d80", "question": "What ABC TV star is the great-grandson of a billionaire oilman?", "answer": "Balthazar Getty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f08c01dd7bf43be5e7fe", "question": "What is the key difference between pizza and flatbread?", "answer": "Yeast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5fc", "question": "What part of a sailor's uniform can be used in an emergency as a flotation device?", "answer": "The pants (also the hat)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c77f877e98cb977789cf", "question": "Why is the Bronx called the Bronx?", "answer": "After a landowner named Jonas Bronck", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a6ef6c0f9723ab15cb58", "question": "What is the only birthstone that is not a mineral?", "answer": "Pearl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59da1b31f6756c9b30ba14f6", "question": "On which river is the city of Mandalay situated?", "answer": "Irrawaddy River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66017a5bfecdd737e0830", "question": "Which president had the most pets at the White House?", "answer": "Calvin Coolidge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec3", "question": "Who was the first Ronald McDonald?", "answer": "Willard Scott", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b803", "question": "What is traditionally broken at the end of a Jewish wedding?", "answer": "A glass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf85", "question": "St Apollonia is the patron saint of what?", "answer": "Dentistry and Toothache", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b81", "question": "Who played Jill Taylor on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Patricia Richardson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd6c97e83c707845b216e", "question": "When was the first Masters Tournament played?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339202", "question": "What do Brad Pitt and Edward Norton shoot at factories while drunk in \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "Golf Balls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63b", "question": "Which blood type is a universal? donor", "answer": "O negative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93a", "question": "What type of athlete is also called a powder puff, tanker, catcher or knuckle duster?", "answer": "A boxer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe1332be39efa6330e0fedb", "question": "Which is the driest, non-polar desert on Earth?", "answer": "Atacama Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff14140b0ee8c595b6d39a2", "question": "What did Pablo Picasso protest in his \"Guernica\" masterpiece?", "answer": "The Spanish Civil War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c5", "question": "Who composed the song \"Rhapsody in Blue\"?", "answer": "George Gershwin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339667", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is Lisa's teacher?", "answer": "Miss Hoover", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a94c9d816e292245c1a", "question": "Coosje van Bruggen and Claes Oldenburg first collaborated on what sculpture?", "answer": "The husband/wife team, first collaborated on\u00a0\"Flashlight\"\u00a0(1981), a huge outdoor sculpture at the University of Nevada, Las Vegas.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe734e4eec85e375820b23e", "question": "Which of Adolf Hitler's close associates fled to Scotland?", "answer": "Rudolph Hess", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a33b", "question": "Which 1980's song includes the lyric \"Creatures crawl in search of blood. To terrorize y'alls neighborhood!\"?", "answer": "Thriller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba45", "question": "What is the official state dessert of Massachusetts?", "answer": "Boston Cream Pie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c5", "question": "How many stars are in the Big Dipper?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e42", "question": "What slave name does Kunta Kinte's owner force him to adopt in Alex Haley's \"Roots\"?", "answer": "Toby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133990d", "question": "What fictitious planet did ALF claim to be an alien from?", "answer": "Melmac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbce", "question": "In the card game Bridge, what is considered the highest of the four suits?", "answer": "Spades", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a713", "question": "Lansing is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1d", "question": "Jefferson City is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41a", "question": "Which Empire was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae1", "question": "Some animals spend the winter in a sleep-like state known as what?", "answer": "Hibernation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b58", "question": "What Broadway Musical is based off the opera \"La Bohem\"?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e84", "question": "What are the zombies, or walkers, on the TV show \"Fear the Walking Dead\" called during season 1?", "answer": "Infected", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6012150063c99d48cd169ae5", "question": "Einstein won the 1921 Nobel Prize for Physics for explaining what?", "answer": "Photoelectric effect -- However, that did not stop him from giving a lecture\u00a0on relativity in his acceptance speech.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5db03e6caa1c9af2684d79a4", "question": "What is the common name for CH3COOH?", "answer": "Acetic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9039c01dd7bf43be5e870", "question": "What is the English translation of the name Keyser Soze?", "answer": "King -- talks unnecessarily too much", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339473", "question": "What is the name of the last human city in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Zion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b22", "question": "When it debuted, what FOX series was promoted as a \"weekly nationwide criminal manhunt\"?", "answer": "America's Most Wanted", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85b", "question": "On which harbour is the Sydney Opera House located?", "answer": "Sydney Harbour", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc9f", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Fistmele\"?", "answer": "Archery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dcf", "question": "What future game show host was the first regular panelist on \"Match Game '73\"?", "answer": "Richard Dawson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a46f", "question": "What is the capital of Belize?", "answer": "Belmopan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a43", "question": "What Bob Marley song did Eric Clapton cover for a #1 hit?", "answer": "I Shot the Sheriff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891f", "question": "What is the name of the dragon in \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "Smaug", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002444a4be4723ccac221a1", "question": "What is the only work of art Michelangelo ever signed?", "answer": "The\u00a0\"Piet\u00e0,\" a masterpiece depicting the body of Jesus on his mother's lap, is the only work of any sort that he ever signed.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad75", "question": "What brothers invented the hot air balloon?", "answer": "Montgolfier", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b0", "question": "What river forms most of the border between the US states Georgia and Alabama?", "answer": "Chattahoochee river", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f742fa9e54d890926f6f4", "question": "What country has competitive office chair racing?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a606", "question": "Which is the largest island of the Inner Hebrides?", "answer": "Skye", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f3", "question": "What is the name the Australian film based on the life of pianist David Helfgott?", "answer": "Shine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a744", "question": "Yellowstone National Park protects the wilderness of what mountain chain?", "answer": "Rocky Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91d", "question": "The Stanley Cup is played for in what sport?", "answer": "Ice hockey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe37adb0ada16518afdc05d", "question": "What role did Herman Goring's brother play during World War II?", "answer": "He helped people escape from concentration camps", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f23", "question": "What was comedian Redd Foxx's real last name?", "answer": "Sanford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6b698fb6c85e9e634ff49", "question": "What country's national flower is the Wattle?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa55b3c73aa70ea0b70b25", "question": "Which Central American country has a name which translates to English as \"The Saviour\"?", "answer": "El Salvador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af62", "question": "What was Typhoid Mary's job?", "answer": "Cook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93c216bd93ce3a4e5f6aa", "question": "The bark of which tree is fireproof?", "answer": "Redwoods", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad84", "question": "Who was the first Russian Czar to westernize Russia?", "answer": "Peter I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecc3b9ec223966ae8f8880", "question": "Barani, Rudolph, and Randolph are techniques in which sports?", "answer": "Trampolining", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f753da9e54d890926f707", "question": "How long is New Zealand\u2019s Ninety Mile Beach?", "answer": "55 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f705ba9e54d890926f6d5", "question": "What is the only South American country to use the U.S. dollar as its official currency?", "answer": "Ecuador -- After a financial crisis in 2000, Ecuador switched from its currency to U.S. dollars due to citizen demand for dollars.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6000eda09a72b906b34e3cef", "question": "What is the fattiest human organ?", "answer": "Brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b4", "question": "What is Nitrous Oxide more commonly known as?", "answer": "Laughing gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b65ae662d71a53651006", "question": "Who played Anita in the first Broadway production of West Side Story?", "answer": "Chita Rivera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a0", "question": "How many gallons does a tun barrel typically hold?", "answer": "252", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc2f26de0eb824d4052e8", "question": "What South American country is a former Dutch colony?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}]